OK, I would say, no matter what.
So for example, take the Second Amendment,
which we kind of danced around.
It's not been covered.
It's come up here and there.
You know the debate about the Second Amendment.
The fundamental debate is one side says it's unlimited.
And the other side says, no, no, what they meant
was the malicious.
They didn't mean, and they had muskets.
They didn't mean AR-15s, right?
So we can have that endless debate, which I really
don't care for about that.
But to come back to your point about the constitutional
principles, the 14th Amendment comes along in the 1860s.
So it's pretty old.
It's not as old as America.
But it comes along.
And it's been around for 150 years.
So if you want to get away with it, you want to get rid of it.
But it was around before 150 million Americans.
And I'm saying it was around before the United States was
even created.
It's part of ancient English common law.
If you're born in a place, you're
a citizen of that place, unless you're
a child of a foreign diplomat or on a Native American
reservation.
English common law did not exist simultaneously
as millions of people coming across the border in a year.
Just to get to principles, your argument
is numbers change everything.
Because we've got so many more people who change the constitution.
Not solely, but absolutely.
The demographics of your immigration
absolutely change it.
Can I ask you a question?
If you got rid of the 14th Amendment,
what would be in its place?
I think a citizenship task would be fantastic.
What age?
I think we could administer it in high school.
To everyone?
Sure.
Or just the immigrants?
No, everybody.
And then if you fail it, you denaturalize
white American native born?
Maybe you can't get a government job.
You can't denaturalize that dude?
I think there's plenty of benefits
that the government offers people that you should not
be able to receive.
I'll tell you this, right?
This might sound bad.
And I think I don't think people care for me anyway.
So let me say something you might not like.
Nobody would pass it.
If you have a high school immigration citizenship
test for everyone, I'm guessing the immigrant kids are going
to outperform the white kids.
And you might actually end up denaturalizing
some of the white kids.
And then people here will be really upset.
And well, hold on.
And I like to be consistent about this.
That's possible.
But what I think it would do is it
would give everybody a larger sense of the importance
of citizenship.
So you would say no one born in this country is a citizen?
No one?
Automatically, no.
I think we could extend that.
You know, people who have a heritage in the country.
What are they until they pass the test?
Undocumented?
I suppose, yeah.
They are not able to receive government benefits.
They're not able to receive government benefits.
They're not able to apply for these jobs that they're
offered.
But they're parents are citizens.
OK, well, hold on.
We're talking here about the way that we would implement it.
Yeah, it's pretty important.
If you're trying to get rid of the 14th Amendment,
I'm going to ask about the practicalities of it.
And we're not going to do it right now.
And I'm not going to be able to explain it to you in 10
minutes.
But what I can explain to you is that right now in this country,
we have a crisis of people not understanding.
Hold on.
We're not understanding what citizenship is.
The way that you've referred to citizenship
makes everybody who hasn't come to the United States
an undocumented American citizen until the time
they come over here.
That's how a lot of countries are, right?
You know that birthright citizenship
is operated by multiple democracies around the world.
I know Trump lies and says, we're
the only country that does it.
He lies.
That's not true.
Multiple countries have birthright citizenship.
Do you think it ought to be that way?
Do you think everybody in the world
is an undocumented American?
So hold on.
Or undocumented Canadian.
Or undocumented Brit, right?
Or undocumented Jew?
Sure.
Well, I'm an American, so I say America.
But yeah, it could be anything.
But I'm saying, right, the principle is you immigrate.
We have free movement.
Do you believe that?
I support free movement of people around the world.
But do you believe they're all undocumented?
Are you Kim Jong-un?
You think people should only stay in one country
and never leave and be blocked from leaving their country?
I think there's a very illiberal,
unconservative position.
I think there's a big room to move between being Kim Jong-un
and saying that it means.
Not really.
In practical terms, if you accept.
I gave one side.
I want to give the other.
There's a big room to move between being Kim Jong-un
and saying that everybody in the world is an American.
They're just not on our soil yet.
I think being an American citizen.
I mean, that's a ridiculous statement, right?
Because everyone in the world is not
heading for the United States of America.
Yes.
In fact, right now, the numbers of people coming in
are dropping a lot.
But the idea that you are supporting
is that the moment you come to this soil
and that you're born here, you become an American.
So I'm not saying at the moment you come to this soil,
you become an American.
I didn't.
I had to do the test.
OK.
I had to do the naturalization process, which
is guaranteed by the 14th Amendment.
But the 14th Amendment also says, if you're born here,
then you automatically get it.
And I'm not saying it's a hill I'm going to die on.
The problem we have is we don't appreciate citizenship.
The problem is that when you talk about immigration
like we did before, when we talked
about everything before, what were we talking about?
We were talking about products.
We weren't talking about practices or perceptions,
which is really what immigration is about.
Can I agree with you?
We don't, in this country, value citizenship enough.
I agree.
I think we should encourage people
to have more civics lessons in schools,
understand American history and Constitution much more.
Here's what the irony is.
I'm sitting in a room today where
I've met a bunch of people claiming
to be Native Americans who hate everything America
stood for for centuries.
I think they stand much closer to the America
that we originally had.
And I think that's the big disagreement.
I don't think any of you live there
or had any clue what that was like.
But you've agreed to dismantling it.
I don't know things about that America.
But you've agreed to dismantling that America
as long as it's legal.
You have.
You're the person who came here and made your argument.
I'm a Constitutional originalist.
Take it away, take it away, an amendment
of the Constitution.
I did.
I said, keep the Second Amendment.
I'm an originalist.
I think we should interpret it the way it was probably
originally interpreted.
All right, guys, that's time.
Nice to speak with you, Kite.
Thank you very much.
Appreciate it.
I thought it would be an interesting exercise in trying
to understand what genuine, far-right, conservative folks
think.
And it was kind of disturbing to see
that they think what I thought they'd think.
And they were happy to say it out loud.
I am disappointed that I had to sit across from people
who believe in white genocide, who believe I'm not a citizen.
Multiple people here said I should be deported.
One of them was even the child of immigrants,
which I found bizarre.
Obviously, we were way outclassed.
Like, we're not professional debaters.
I don't think anyone in this room was.
Maybe one or two people.
And clearly, Manny, he does this for a living, right?
He's a journalist.
So he's really good at what he does.
Mehdi Hassan was pretty good at taking cheap shots,
trying to derail people from their arguments,
trying to pit me against some of the people
that wouldn't like people of my color
to be in the United States, which is irrelevant.
I think one person said, if you walked off,
you'll be the first to go, which is ominous and racist.
I think that was disheartening and particularly discouraging,
because it just felt like it was fitting into a stereotype
that we're trying to fight against,
which is like, we actually have arguments.
We can provide good reason.
And that rhetoric just pushes that far away.
I am, I guess, a far-right Republican.
But as I learned today, not as far-right
as I thought I was.
You know, someone gets up and they're just like,
yeah, I mean, I guess I just want to have, like,
autocracy forever and Christian nationalism,
or just being like, yeah, I'm racist.
And to me, that's very foreign of a concept.
While I didn't, you know, disagree with most of the people
in the circle, it did bother me at times, you know,
to see them say mean things.
There's not really a reason to do that.
But it also upset me when Mehdi said, you know,
I'm not willing to debate with those people.
Free speech doesn't mean you need to give credibility
or oxygen or a platform to people who don't agree
in human equality.
I hear Mehdi's point about not giving them a platform.
But the thing is, if you stop giving them a platform,
they don't just go away and change their mind.
And then you tell the rest of society,
no one exists who thinks like that.
And that's not true.
I do like to debate people, even people I disagree with.
I try and avoid bad faith folks.
I think some of the folks today were bad faith.
You know, I'm anti-conservative, right?
I don't support conservative views on taxation.
I don't support conservative views on immigration.
But the people here today were way beyond conservatives.
This is open authoritarianism.
And this is what is being normalized and mainstreamed
in our country by people in power, by the media,
by people who don't know any better.